Uh obviously very excited, you know, our
top rated dual return player. Uh and in
this new dynamic kickoff age of the
National Football League, uh to have a
guy that's, you know, in our opinion,
very good at both, uh we think it's
going to be a a a major addition and and
pay dividends for the club.
>> Questions? You have to sell hard for
this or was this pretty much a universal
let's go get this guy? you know, we go
through the draft process and and have
our meetings and, you know, everybody
gives their opinion on players and once
that done, I I really I don't go
anywhere near the draft room. I let the
the professionals do their job. U
obviously there seems to be a good
consensus that uh you know, he was a a
high level player that can that can help
the club uh to victories, which is again
the only thing any of us are worried
about is hanging W's. So, we think this
is a player that can help us do that.
being what they are on game day. Stepped
up just a return guy. So, how do you
think he can help you guys offensively?
And how did that show in the limited
chances that he's had in college?
>> Yeah, obviously offensive guys will will
will figure that out. And that's just
that's part of the National Football
League. That's part of the process. You
know, every player that comes in the
building, you know, the more roles you
can find for every single guy as part of
it. So, you know, I'm I don't know if
you asked, you know, about the offensive
tackle or the corner or the wide
receiver, but every single guy that's
going to be in this building, you know,
everybody has to be ready to put their
hands on them and find a way to use
them. And those are the guys that, you
know, on game day will have uniforms and
and help the football club because you
said you were the only official
interview we had, what did you guys see
in him that no one else did? Well, I'm
sure a lot of people saw the same thing
that that we did. Uh, just like a lot of
these players in the draft, it's all
about, you know, the the timing and and
availability of when you have the, you
know, the the chance to maybe add a
player. So, you know, there's a lot of
players that we like um that we will not
get a chance or did not have a chance to
get because of, you know, how the draft
board fell. You know, we were fortunate
that this was a player that we liked and
was available at a spot where uh we were
able to get him. So, very excited.
>> What makes him a good What makes him a
good returner?
>> Number one, he makes great decisions,
good ball security, and then he is what
I refer to as he's a catch, run, cut
player. You know, a lot of guys, you
know, are looking to cut be maybe before
they need to. He is fearless. Um, and
he's not going to make the cuts till he
has to, and he can do it late. uh he's
good in a tight area, can make the
shallow cuts. So, really brings a really
good skill set uh in the return game and
especially how you know the with the new
rules and kickoff return, you know,
those vertical one cut runners uh have
been very successful over the last
couple years and we think that's what uh
what he'll bring to the Steelers.
>> Danny, you talk about it being rare guys
are good punk returners and kick
returners. Why do you think that is and
what is the key characteristic of
someone that's good at both? You know,
it's they're two completely different
things. That that's the first thing. You
know, the the catching the ball on punts
is completely different than any other
catch you will make. Uh because of the
spin and the rotation of the ball based
on a right foot or left footed and where
it's going to go and how to read that
and adjust to it even before you get
into elements, wind, rain, sun. So,
being able to read the ball uh and make
good decisions and then to be fearless
enough to make late decisions uh and
what you're going to do and to be able
to help yourself to be able to create
space in doing that,
>> right? How how have the new kick returns
changed maybe the body type or the skill
set that you're looking for from that
specific
>> and and that's an ongoing process
because this will be the third year in a
row that they've they've tweaked the the
alignment rules for the kickoff return.
You know, I think you guys will all
agree uh that it it's brought some
bigger bodies back into the mix. You
know, years and years ago, you know, you
saw a lot of those big bodies in the
back end in the wedge u in the kickoff
return game and then it's became more of
a spatial game. Those guys disappeared.
I think this close combat, for lack of a
better term, uh has brought some of
those larger bodies back in. But now
having the ability to flex up to four
people in return game, it's going to
give it another little little twist and
and we'll see what that leads to. But uh
it's it's now a it's a major play as you
guys know. It's it's not a play that's
disappeared, thank goodness. Uh because
it is exciting play uh especially if you
uh you know when you have a guy back
there that can can be creative and make
something big happen. We just got to
know Kaden a little bit in the draft
call, but what did you see out of him
personalitywise that makes him a good
returner?
>> You know what? I I don't know that. You
know, I was if I had to do it over
again, I'd probably go back and be a
psychology, early childhood education
major to to get into coaching instead of
business. But, you know, he plays the
game fearlessly, but he plays it smart.
So he makes good decisions which is
paramount you know the respect of the
ball and you guys will get to like
respect the ball that's the only thing
that matters when whoever has the ball
has everybody's lives in their hands and
he makes good decisions he doesn't make
bad decisions to put himself i.e which
leads to the team and bad positions. Uh
so good decision maker, good ball
security and then he is very dynamic
with the ball in his hands.
>> I know you have two years of data to go
off but has because of the new NFL
kickoff somebody obviously was
ridiculously successful college
returning kickoff is a different
>> is the rule does that translate? Have
you seen the the good college kickoff
people be good in the NFL kickoff? Yeah.
Again, I'm with not enough data to
determine that. But when you watch
like you do with all evaluations, the
college the college game is com it's a
lot different than the NFL game. I don't
care whether you're talking offensive,
defense, or in the kick game. You know,
they're different games, but you find
those those glimpses and those things
that do translate where you can see a
lateral late vertical cut, which you can
see and see how that will translate um
into what's happening in the National
Football League, but the ball security
and decision-m and also some not great
weather, like all those things tie into,
you know, some things that we were
looking for and uh you know, we think we
got a very good player. Kaitton started
playing at running back when he was
first playing football. How do you see
that running back background come up as
a return? Do you see that the vision,
the way he kind of takes angles in the
paths?
>> You can see that I I don't I don't worry
about that. But you can see he's got a
great feel on on who, how, when to cut,
what moves to make, when to make those
moves. Again, you see a lot of guys that
make moves on air. Uh, so we we we think
we we got a very good player who has a a
good history and we think it's going to
translate that history to the National
Football League.
>> I know he's not the biggest guy, Danny,
but can he potentially run down and
cover kicks and
>> punks or again, everybody that that
comes in this building will find and
give opportunities uh to try and do as
many things as possible. you know, the
more guys that you have uh that can do
multiple things because that's that's
the nature of the game. you know, on
game day, whether even if you are the
starter or the backup throughout the
course of a game, you know, you're going
to play guys that, you know, maybe it's
not their ideal role, but you got to get
them ready for it, and you got to make
them successful when they go on the